<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on blog</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>© dima 2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 10:52:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Track a website by diff and get notification</title><link>/post/2024-08-07-track-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 10:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>/post/2024-08-07-track-website/</guid><description>Some day, I needed to keep track of my daughter&amp;rsquo;s schools wordPress page about news. As a software developer, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to check the website every day, so I decided to use a third-party service like Telegram to get notified whenever there were new updates.
My idea was to fetch the entire page&amp;rsquo;s content and transform it into Markdown format, removing all HTML tags to leave only the readable content.</description></item><item><title>Yubikey - rule them all</title><link>/post/2024-06-16-yubikey-configuration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2024-06-16-yubikey-configuration/</guid><description>Finally I have one(two cause of backup) Yubikey 5 NFC and FINALLY I took the time to dig deeper into private security.
Here I will provide long story short summary about my learnings and a quick howto.
Download tails image to USB and boot it Create secure passphrase with this commands, or with helper like passphrase.html or passphrase.csv after print lp -d Printer-Name passphrase.csv or with Dicewire CERTIFY_PASS=$(LC_ALL=C tr -dc &amp;#39;A-Z1-9&amp;#39; &amp;lt; /dev/urandom | \ tr -d &amp;#34;1IOS5U&amp;#34; | fold -w 30 | sed &amp;#34;-es/.</description></item><item><title>Rails - drop database data</title><link>/post/2024-01-30-rails-reset-data-except-some/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2024-01-30-rails-reset-data-except-some/</guid><description>If you want to drop your data in rails you do it usually with bin/rails db:drop or bin/rails db:schema:load. But if you have a case, you need to keep some data in different tables, you need to do it with a specific Rake task.
I had a case for a demo environment, where we are reseting all data every sunday for presentations. But we have some tables with &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo; calculation data for different use-cases, that we need to skip in resetting task and skip at re-seeding job.</description></item><item><title>Pair programming with tmux</title><link>/post/2018-12-11-tmux-pair-programming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2018-12-11-tmux-pair-programming/</guid><description>The simpliest way to develop over the network with a colleague or friend in a secure way, is to use ssh[1] and tmux[2]. An alternative is to use a very popular tool named tmate[3]. In my opinion, it is not necessary, because it is so simple to create a new user on your machine and to share your tmux session with them. Only if you haven&amp;rsquo;t a ssh incoming routing, you may use another way.</description></item><item><title>Create a perfect pgp key</title><link>/post/2018-06-12-create-a-perfect-pgp-key/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2018-06-12-create-a-perfect-pgp-key/</guid><description>Maybe I already said that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of pass. A small unix tool (bash-script) for managing passwords with a pgp-key. In this note I collected some introductions for a best practise.
The goals in this post are create a pgp master key with multiple id and a subkey.
GPG config At first, some gpg config stuff here. [1]
Update your ~/.gnupg/gpg.conf and kill your actually running gpg-agent killall gpg-agent</description></item><item><title>Arch installation</title><link>/post/2018-06-11-arch-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2018-06-11-arch-installation/</guid><description>I was a long time a macbook fanboy. After some wired news about apples macOS, some bugs and so on, I had decide to switch to arch-linux. The os that I use already at work, and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with that. So, after this decision i sold macbook and bought a dell xps 13 9370. Now I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post on my new xps with arch.
USB drive Create a bootable usb drive with a arch iso (for beginner: antergos live iso):</description></item><item><title>Wildfly LDAP integration</title><link>/post/2018-01-08-wildfly-ldap-intergration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2018-01-08-wildfly-ldap-intergration/</guid><description>In the past, I spent a lot of time to figuring out, how to add the integrated LDAP module of the wildfly server. To do this, you have to take changes in some different places:
Wildfly server side Add &amp;lsquo;LDAPExtended&amp;rsquo; module in wildfly configuration In the first place you have to add a module to your server configuration. Do it like this: Wildfly admin console: Configuration -&amp;gt; Subsystems -&amp;gt; Security -&amp;gt; [Add] Name: &amp;quot;LDAPAuth&amp;quot; this name will be connected in the jboss-web.</description></item><item><title>Wildfly DLL as extension</title><link>/post/2018-01-22-wildfly-dll-as-extension/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2018-01-22-wildfly-dll-as-extension/</guid><description>A very difficult part of a wildfly instance is to use some DLL-files in your different java projects as dependency. If you choose the easy way and include the dll binary in your executable path of your wildfly instance, your war project will crash after an another project try to use the same dll binary. After that cognition you have to go the &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; way. In this post you are on the right path&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Passwordstore extension: pass-file</title><link>/post/2017-12-18-pass-file-extension/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2017-12-18-pass-file-extension/</guid><description>I am a big fan of the unix password-store, one of that which I used every day. And the best of it, thats only a bash script.
After some years of using keepass in a Dropbox and a keyfile on usb storage, I find this some little tool. It&amp;rsquo;s absolutly perfect, cause I am a big fan of CLI apps, too :). On the mobile way I use the open source app for iOS, thats a really good addition.</description></item></channel></rss>